voxcdn.com 2012-12-19

# Internap Global Hosting Company Privacy Policy — Internap

## Internap – IT Infrastructure solutions provider featuring enterprise IP, CDN, colocation, managed hosting and cloud services

Internap respects the privacy of every individual who visits this website, provides personal information to us via interactive features of this website, or sends e-mails to Internap via this website. This privacy policy discusses the information that may be collected via this website and how Internap may use that information. In the event that you do not want your personal information collected or shared when you visit this website or send us e-mails via this website, please refer to the procedures described below. This privacy statement does not cover our use of information collected through any other means.

### Collection and Use of Personally Identifiable Information

**Personally Identifiable Information**  
The information Internap obtains from you is generally necessary or useful for Internap to provide the services or information you have requested and to design new services for your future use, and is provided directly by you in response to Internap’s request for the information. In connection with the services Internap provides, Internap may ask you to provide your name, physical address, ZIP code, phone number, e-mail address, and services received or requested. Your submission of such information online is deemed your consent to Internap’s use of the information as contemplated in this privacy policy.

**How We Use the Information**  
Generally, Internap uses the information, and other information Internap may have about you, to provide the services or information you have requested, to personalize your experience on this website, to provide customer support, to improve this website, to enforce Internap’s agreements and policies, to resolve disputes, to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, and to design new services for your future use.

Internap may also use the information to notify you about new services or offers that Internap may have available, or to provide news about Internap.

Internap may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your personal information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party.

**When We Share the Information**  
Internap shares information within our organization to enable us to better understand our customers’ service needs, and to learn how to best design, develop, and deliver services to meet those needs.  
Internap does not sell, rent, or lease its customer lists to unaffiliated third parties for their marketing purposes without your consent.

Internap occasionally hires other companies to provide services on its behalf, such as handling the processing and delivery of mailings, providing customer support and service offerings, processing transactions, or performing statistical analysis of our services. They are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information and are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

Internap may access and/or disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary: (a) to conform to the mandates of the law or comply with legal process served on Internap; (b) to protect and defend the rights or property of Internap; (c) to act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of our services or members of the public, (d) to respond to legal requests, or (e) in connection with the sale of all or substantially all of our assets to which this website relates.

While we use commercially reasonable efforts to ensure that our use and disclosure of your personally identifiable information as described in our privacy statement, we cannot ensure that your communications with us will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this privacy statement.

**Other Information We Collect**  
Some information may automatically be collected as you browse our site. Our web server automatically collects information such as the domain name of the service providing you with Internet access, the Internet Protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, the average time spent on our site, pages viewed, information searched for, access times, and other relevant statistics.

We also use cookies on our site. A cookie is a small data file that websites commonly write to the site visitor’s hard drive when a site is visited. A cookie file contains information that can identify a return visitor each time he or she visits our site. The data is encrypted for added security. Internap’s website may use cookies as a way to measure activity and traffic patterns on the site in order to continually improve the visitor’s experience. A browser can be set to warn the user before accepting cookies. Users can choose to refuse cookies by turning them off in the browser. Users do not need to have cookies turned on to visit our website.

**Your Choices**  
We do not collect personally identifiable information about you on this website without your knowledge, and all such information is collected directly from you. You are not required to provide us with this information; however, if you choose not to provide such information, you may not be able to participate in some of the activities on this website.

We use the information we collect from you to allow you to participate in the site activities for which the information is collected. For example, when you give us your e-mail address in order to receive newsletters, information regarding our services, and special promotions, your e-mail address will be added to our marketing database. Internap will only send e-mails to visitors that request Internap send them this information. Internap will not send commercial solicitations via e-mail to customers who request that they not be sent to them. On each e-mail you receive, you are given the opportunity to unsubscribe. In addition, you can “opt-out” by sending an e-mail to [unsubscribe@Internap.com](mailto:%75%6E%73%75%62%73%63%72%69%62%65%40%49%6E%74%65%72%6E%61%70%2E%63%6F%6D). Once you unsubscribe, you will no longer receive such e-mails.

**Transfers of Information**  
Because Internap operates from its headquarters in Atlanta, Georgia and through subsidiary companies located in several countries around the world, and because its web servers, which host ours websites, are located at various locations within and outside of the U.S., it is possible that personal information about visitors may be transferred from one country to another. In particular, your personally identifiable information will likely be processed in the U.S. or Canada, where data protection and privacy regulations may not offer the same level of protection as in other parts of the world, such as the European Union, and are considered inadequate by the European Union. By providing us with your information, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country.

**Access and Review**  
If you have questions regarding your personally identifiable information that we have collected via this website, or which to change or delete such data from our active databases, please contact us at [privacyinfo@internap.com](mailto:%70%72%69%76%61%63%79%69%6E%66%6F%40%49%6E%74%65%72%6E%61%70%2E%63%6F%6D).

**Children and Privacy**  
Internap does not knowingly collect information from or about children under 13 years of age.

**Security**  
Internap maintains its databases and systems in accordance with industry standards to reasonably secure all of Internap’s commercial information, including information about customers. However, you should be aware that absolute security does not exist on the Internet, and that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable.

### Enforcement

Internap complies with the U.S. – EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Internap has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view our certification page, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

In compliance with the Safe Harbor Principles, Internap commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Internap at:

Greta Van  
VP Audit and Compliance  
Internap Network Services Corp.  
One Ravinia Drive, Suite 1300  
Atlanta, GA 30346  

Internap has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU Safe Harbor, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by Internap, please visit the BBB EU Safe Harbor website at [www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints](http://www.bbb.org/us/european-dispute-resolution/consumer/) for more information and to file a complaint.

### Changes to Policy

If Internap decides to change its privacy policies and practices, Internap will post those changes to our Privacy Policy on our website in advance of the changes taking effect, so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner from that point forward. We will continue to be able to use information in accordance with the Privacy Policy under which the information was collected or, if you have given consent, under the modified Privacy Policy.

May 2012
